{
  "age": 60,
  "aliases": [
    "/state-house/district-17/kumar-p-barve/"
  ],
  "background": "Professionally, I am an accountant and the CFO of a company in Rockville.",
  "directory": "content/primary/state-house/district-17",
  "district": 17,
  "dob": "9/8/1958",
  "education": "Georgetown University, Bachelor of Science, Accounting, 1980  Attended K-12 in the Montgomery County Public School System",
  "filename": "kumar-p-barve.md",
  "full-name": "Kumar P. Barve",
  "general-only": false,
  "jurisdiction": "Montgomery County",
  "last-name": "Barve",
  "party": "Democrat",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Do you support the findings of the Commission on Innovation and Excellence in Education? Are you committed to funding associated reforms, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "I support the Kirwin and Knott Commission reports, and I supported the creation of the constitutional \"lockbox\" which will result in an additional $500 million in education funding.",
      "shortname": "Kirwan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is Maryland’s transportation spending appropriately balanced between roads and transit? Does the state have the resources to meet its transportation needs? With the cancellation of the Red Line and the advent of BaltimoreLink, is the Baltimore region adequately served by transit?",
      "answer": "The Governor dis-served the Baltimore region by canceling the Red Line. Baltimore Link is not an adequate  solution to Baltimore's transit needs.",
      "shortname": "Transportation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the legalization of recreational marijuana?",
      "answer": "Yes. It should be legalized, regulated and taxed.",
      "shortname": "Marijuana"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a time when the federal government’s commitment to Chesapeake Bay restoration is questionable, what new steps should Maryland take to protect this resource?",
      "answer": "First, I immediately opposed Governor Hogan's cancellation of the phosphorous management tool regulations and forced him to the table to implement regulations that would work. Under my term as the Chairman of the Environment & Transportation Committee, the Chesapeake Bay's status has been upgraded. I think we should continue to refine and tighten pollution regulations to protect the Bay.",
      "shortname": "Chesapeake Bay"
    },
    {
      "question": "What steps should Maryland take to ensure the broadest possible access to affordable health care?",
      "answer": "I think we made great progress this year taking actions to ensure the stability of the ACA. In the future I think we need to move in the direction of regulating the price of prescription drugs.",
      "shortname": "Health Care"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the state play in helping Baltimore address violent crime?",
      "answer": "I think the state should continue to spend record amounts of money in the City.",
      "shortname": "Crime"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you characterize Maryland’s business climate? What can the state do to foster the creation of more family-supporting jobs?",
      "answer": "I am the father of TEDCO one of the nation's most successful high-tech job creating entities according to an independant analysis of conducted by Battelle: http://tedco.md/press/tedco-generates-1-billion-in-economic-impact-4358-jobs-to-maryland-economy/",
      "shortname": "Business Climate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the creation of a non-partisan, independent body to draw legislative and congressional district maps after each census?",
      "answer": "I support independent redistricting commissions to set congressional districts as long as all states participate. Gerrymandering in states like Pennsylvania, Texas and Ohio has resulted in a permanent institutional GOP majority despite a majority of Americans voting for Democratic congressional candidates. I also support independent commissions for state redistricting.",
      "shortname": "Redistricting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the public? Should it be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "",
      "shortname": "LEOBR"
    },
    {
      "question": "What strategy would you adopt to address the opioid addiction and overdose crisis?",
      "answer": "This year we established a competitive grant program that awards funding to local behavioral health organizations to expand capabilities of crisis response programs and services. Services and programs include: mobile crisis teams, 24/7 walk-in services, crisis residential beds, and other crisis response programs. Total funding for annual grants begins in 2020 at $3 million, $4 million in 2021, and $5 million in 2022.",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What if anything should the state do to address income inequality?",
      "answer": "Maryland is already a leader in so many ways. We have raised the minimum wage, we have a very generous eraned income tax credit, we spend more than all but a few states on K-16 education.",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do the state’s Public Information Act and open meetings laws adequately ensure Marylanders’ ability to exercise oversight of the government?",
      "answer": "Yes",
      "shortname": "Transparency"
    }
  ],
  "race": "state-house",
  "residence": "Rockville",
  "social-fb": "BarveforMaryland/",
  "social-tw": "kumarbarve",
  "survey-response": true,
  "title": "Kumar P. Barve",
  "web": "http://www.kumarbarve.com"
}
